<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ideas on MikeDixson.com</title>
    <link>https://mikedixson.com/categories/ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ideas on MikeDixson.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 11:33:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mikedixson.com/categories/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Could 3D Printing be Internet Dating’s Next Step?</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/could-3d-printing-be-internet-datings-next-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 11:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/could-3d-printing-be-internet-datings-next-step/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s occurred to me that it doesn’t matter how many photos you see of a prospective Internet date you see the reality on date night can often be a very different one indeed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst reading about some 3D printing technology recently I thought that a possible next step for Internet Dating could be for dating websites to require a front and profile shot uploaded and they could then render a 3D model on the website for prospective partners to view. Going one step further you could make a 3D print of the face, maybe at designated 3D print house which are spreading rapidly, the prospective partner could then get a real sense of the person before meeting them and avoid any awkward first dates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively it could just be really creepy to print off strangers faces.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self Imposed Poverty – How to force yourself to save more</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/self-imposed-poverty-how-to-force-yourself-to-save-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 01:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/self-imposed-poverty-how-to-force-yourself-to-save-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people would say money burns a hole in my pocket, that’s not entirely true, I’m not as frugal as some, but I enjoy the money I do have and have enough to get buy on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But&lt;/strong&gt;, I’m trying to save to buy a property and so every penny counts. Changing your spending habits takes discipline and saving as much as I need to in the time that I want to takes a lot of saving, thus a lot of discipline.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So I’ve been trying out self imposed poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As with most of you, in the last week of a month I’m pretty poor, and start spending more frugally, watching what I spend more, making the cheaper choices and so on. So what if I move the poverty line? What if I shift the date when the pinch hits forward to midway through the month?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So the last couple of months after I get paid and my regular transfer to my savings occurs, I transfered an extra £100 to my savings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So now I’m poorer sooner, but start spending more frugally sooner. Even if I need grab that money back towards the end of the month I’m not dipping into my regular savings, and I’ve already started spending more frugally by then anyway, so will have still made some in roads to spending less that month than I otherwise would have.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what do you reckon? Think you can try and impose some poverty on yourself for your own greater good?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache mod_rewrite Redirecting Directories Without Looping</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/apache-mod_rewrite-redirecting-directories-without-looping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 03:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/apache-mod_rewrite-redirecting-directories-without-looping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow! It’s true what they say, mod_rewrite rules are a dark art, and whilst I’ve combed the Internet to find, what I thought would be a simple redirect, I’ve found countless examples that didn’t work.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So now I have one that does work I’m sharing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;goal&#34;&gt;Goal&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To redirect hits to a subdomain sshwindows.webheat.co.uk to a subdirectory (in my case cause that is the link to the page within my wiki) /display/sshwindows/&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traffic to any other domain hosted on this same server should &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be redirected.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All &lt;strong&gt;without looping&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; conditions not just one. Check the host header &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; the uri to ensure the root had been hit, and only then redirect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;RewriteEngine On&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; RewriteCond %{HTTP_HOST} ^sshwindows.webheat.co.uk$ [NC]&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; RewriteCond %{REQUEST_URI} /$&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; RewriteRule ^(.*)?$ http://sshwindows.webheat.co.uk/display/sshwindows [L]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For me I put this into my /etc/apache2/sites-enabled/000-default file, but you can equally put this into a .htaccess file. For me this was to be a global thing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;additional-notes&#34;&gt;Additional Notes&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The [nc] is the no-case flag to make the host header match case-insensitive.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The [L] is the Last flag, so after this rule no further ones will be processed. In all honesty I don’t need this here, but that part came from another source and it’s 4am so I’ll be damned if I’m going to remove it now when it’s all working 🙂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tablet’s will not cure all that ails you</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/tablets-will-not-cure-all-that-ails-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 18:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/tablets-will-not-cure-all-that-ails-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I read the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://mashable.com/2012/01/16/tablet-education/&#34;&gt;Tablets Will Transform the Classroom [OPINION]&lt;/a&gt; I found myself getting increasingly frustrated at this article’s view on what Tablets like the iPad, Galaxy Tab, etc would bring to the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scraping texts books is one thing, though I suggest that many publishers are still dragging there heels into this century, afraid that everyone will automatically pirate all books and their cash flow will disappear. Text books are heavy and dull, and largely in some ugly typeface that is hard on the eyes, so by all means makes them available as an ebook.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;However &lt;a title=&#34;Posts by Neil Johnston&#34; href=&#34;http://mashable.com/author/neil-johnston/&#34; rel=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Neil Johnston&lt;/a&gt; believes that tablet computers will enable teacher to facilitate teaching at different speeds/levels in a single class. I’m unclear how this magic would happen, unless the under paid teacher is likely to want to spend three times the amount of time working on class plans for three different levels that all tie in together at key points so that the teacher can orate on them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m all for students learning at their own levels, I believe that it encourages great growth and keeps students interested in their studies, instead of waiting for everyone to catch up with you or feeling like you are never going to catch up to others.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;But this is more an argument for virtual learning environment(online learning), and having the whole class plan/notes available and having students progress at a pace that is comfortable to them. In this case the teach becomes almost like a project manager, ensuring that the students stay on schedule for their milestones, but allowing students who are so inclined to zoom ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This would also allow for some learning disabilities to be catered for, larger text for people with learning disabilities, colour schemes adjusted for accessibility, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do agree that this is an excellent opportunity for academia to get with the times, but in order to do that teachers/lecturers need to get up to speed, and be completely competent with the Operating System and Office applications at least.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Students need to emerge out of  secondary school completely familiar with computers and, perhaps more importantly, the ability to investigate and work out how to use a new applications or systems without having to be walked thru it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tablet is not a magic bullet, no bit of technology is really, but how people use technology and continue to do so is important, and the future of computing in the classroom depends on all parties involved investing themselves in the technology, not being afraid to work with it and to be creative in the ideas that they come up with for how the can get more use out of the technology in the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Put Your Friends In Boxes</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/why-you-should-put-your-friends-in-boxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 08:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/why-you-should-put-your-friends-in-boxes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve fairly recently entered into a new relationship after my last one ended about a year before. When I broke up with my last girlfriend Facebook became a bit of a painful experience for me, seeing everyone having such a great time when I was feeling down in the dumps but more so because Facebook had a plethora of photos of me and my ex-girlfriend on at various events we’d been to over the years together.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As they were painful to ok through I didn’t go thru and remove all of them, I just ended up stopping looking at them. In time it was no longer painful and I moved on but I didn’t bother going back thru all my photos to delete&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve entered a new relationship and, of course, my new girlfriend isn’t too happy about seeing photos of me and my ex on Facebook. As such I’m faced with the labourious task of taking all the photos down or changing the permissions so that my girlfriend can’t see them.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As more than just my ex and I are in these albums and the others in those albums might like the photos of them and want to keep them online still, changing the permissions seems like a logical option. Note, that’s man logic, girlfriend logic would probably dictate that I’m keeping them online so I can look through them whenever I want. I’m going to work with man logic for this post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So if you want to prevent your new girlfriend from seeing photos of you and your ex by exclusion then you’d need to go through each album the very instant you add your girlfriend on Facebook and add her as someone who can’t see this album.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Far better than when you start dating a new girlfriend you put her and friends who are likely to be in the albums with you, into one Facebook friend list, then only allow access to that group.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;That way if you need someone to see those photos you have to add them to that group, rather then have to hide it from whomever you need to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As such it seems like putting your friends, and girlfriends into little boxes is the best way to ensure that people don’t see what they don’t want to see.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security: Where’s The App For That?</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/security-wheres-the-app-for-that/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 16:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/security-wheres-the-app-for-that/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you might be on the ball enough to change your Facebook, or Google settings to use HTTPS, the secure way to browse websites. However when you fire up your Facebook or your bank app on your smart phone are you still being smart? Is it using secure protocols to talk to the servers or is everything you do being sent in clear text over your coffee shop’s wireless network.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s reasonable to assume that the lack of up roar from the geek community means it is secure, but with no visual indication of this end users aren’t to know. Stats mentioned in the news lately suggest that app usage is starting to outstrip website usage. This is fine for most end users, however it should be done right and securely, and there should be transparency if this security to the end user.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time O’The Signs</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/time-othe-signs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 17:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/time-othe-signs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com&#34;&gt;gizmodo.com&lt;/a&gt;, and email a couple of webbased service pricing changes that affect me came to light this week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mozy.com&#34;&gt;Mozy.com&lt;/a&gt; is cutting it’s unlimited service to a tiered pricing system. There’s a couple of things that suck about this, firstly a service that was costing me in the region of £3 per month, and I was backing up 350GB too was now going to cost me over £22, and secondly they only gave half a month’s notice in which to decide and either migrate your data or pay up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now it took me the best part of a month to back up my data in the first place with Mozy.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I’m now in the process of backing up to Carbonite which will cost £5 a month for unlimited backups.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can see that an unlimited model can be unsustainable, you will always end up with some people abusing it, but with that sort of offer you are playing the averages game, assuming that most won’t and so are covering the costs of those who will.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Why they jumped the pricing up quite so much I do not know. They are going to lose customers in great swathes.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;They cited trying to make customers more aware of the data they are backing up, but surely this defeats the set it and forget it motto that they use to sell the product in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m curious why they opted for a model which costs users so steeply. Switich to Carbonite has nearly doubled my cost of back up but is still a negligible cost for an offsite backup for me, where as Mozy’s new model was a hike I couldn’t swallow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://last.fm&#34;&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; is the other network based service that is changing it’s pricing model. Now wanting users to have premium accounts in order to stream to devices.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I’ve got no issue with a great service like Last.fm trying to have a workable long term model, but I think this change is lacking in a couple of ways.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I use a Sonos S5 for my music needs at home, and often stream Last.FM via it, in fact far more than I used to on my computer. Thru Last.fm I discovered new artists based on artists I already liked or by listening to Last.fm ‘radio’ stations based on a tag. If I liked a artist enough I’d go and buy their album.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So here’s a few thoughts, shouldn’t the record companies be paying Last.fm a subscription fee to keep playing artists on their label and enabling new listeners to find their artists.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Also now, I can listen to Last.fm for free on my computer and even put that thru a line out into my Sonos to get the same audio quality, but I can’t use my Sonos S5 to listen to last.fm directly without paying £3 a month.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Maybe they should move to an ad supports free version like Spotify and premium users get no ads.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;My issue is that for £3 a month, I get the same service I’ve had for free for years, nothing extra as far as I can see, no exclusive offers, or even the option to choose which artist’s album I want to listen to and listening to in it’s entirety, no I get to listen to a random selection of songs based on one criteria I specify.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;At which point I have to question, do I pay £3 for discovering music, or do I pay £10 for spotify and then get the option to listen to albums I want to hear and be able to download them for offline playing on my iPhone?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Last.FM I’m an advocate of yours, I want you to succeed, I want to support you, but you’re not offering me anything that I can’t get for free. Innovate to survive, please!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s in the future for the iPad?</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/whats-in-the-future-for-the-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2010 22:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/whats-in-the-future-for-the-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-72&#34; title=&#34;Apple ipad&#34; src=&#34;http://www.webheat.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/06/4494584895_f0ecd43255_t.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Apple ipad&#34; width=&#34;85&#34; height=&#34;100&#34; /&gt;I’ve been a bit quiet hear so far this month whilst my work get’s busier, but that’s not to say I’m not constantly thinking about technology and our future with it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At best I can only see I’ll use it as a portable web reader for reading web documents away from my desk.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For instance the other day I had a couple of web documents that I needed to get my head around so I printed them both and went off somewhere quiet to get into the documents. However, any decent eReader can provide a similar function, though admitedly I’d need to print to PDF the docs and load them to the eReader.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Either way an iPad seems a bit of over kill for that. Maybe the apps that come to the iPad will make it more essential.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For now I’ll stick with my iPhone to fill the app gap.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is the Future of Transport in London</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/this-is-the-future-of-transport-in-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 17:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/this-is-the-future-of-transport-in-london/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gizmodo posted an interesting article today &lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/5530730/b+cycle-the-gps+equipped-bike-sharing-system-i-want-right-now&#34;&gt;http://gizmodo.com/5530730/b+cycle-the-gps+equipped-bike-sharing-system-i-want-right-now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is very similar to a cycle system I was envisaging for London about 6 years ago except more techie. GPS wasn’t so prevalent when I was dreaming up my idea but both ideas contain the key factor. The fact that you can pick up a bike from one location and drop it off at another.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For years I travelled into work, the majority of my journey being on an overground rail line into London Bridge station and then I had to negotiate the shorter distance to Shoreditch. I looked into getting a folder bike at the time but I would have nowhere to store it at/near work.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As such I resorted to buses and tubes, much preferring to be above ground when possible, especially in summer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More recently I live within walking distance of a tube line and have got rid of my car as driving across London was an unpredictable drain on time, any one incident on the way could add between 30 to 60 minutes on a journey. Many of the journeys I could get a tube, but many more I would happily have been able to cycle had I had anywhere to store my bike at the other end. London is addressing this with more and more cycle rack to lock your bike to, but when you want to be able to change plans at a moments notice, as is common in the thriving London you having the system that Trek is putting in place in Denver makes even more sense.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness of Technology</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/mindfulness-of-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 21:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/mindfulness-of-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/tinybuddha&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/tinybuddha&#34;&gt;www.twitter.com/tinybuddha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;‘s post &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/dwYuNh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/dwYuNh&#34;&gt;http://bit.ly/dwYuNh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I’m inspired to think 2 things:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is no digital replacement for a hug. So hug someone.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can use the batteries in your life to regulate some good habits. For instance. If your mobile’s battery is running low at the end of the day, think you’ve done at least as much work and so should do something positive. Meditate, switch off, recharge by sleeping. You could also pull the power from your laptop and use the battery life of your laptop to regulate you taking a breaking. Stash your charger in a drawer so you can’t just whack it on charge quickly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rise up and make TV! Public Access Internet Channel</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/rise-up-and-make-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2010 15:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/rise-up-and-make-tv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve had the revolution of the Facebook masses getting Rage Against The Machine to number one instead of the latest corporate produced (s)hit from Simon Cowell. So how about the same for tv.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Now we don’t have a tv chart that we can influence so directly as we do with music, more’s the pity. But how about we rally together and start out own online tv station. I know some great script wrtiters and actors who do some very interesting projects, why not bring those to the masses and generate excitement about online?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With any luck the mass media will pay some attention and maybe start putting more challenging programming on. Or at the very least some of the amazing talent out there will get recognized and taken on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic TV guides, the future of tv</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/semantic-tv-guides-the-future-of-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/semantic-tv-guides-the-future-of-tv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been laid up lately with a broken leg and consequentially I’ve been watching a lot of tv. I’ve been surprised that there’s actually &lt;strong&gt;some&lt;/strong&gt; good shows out there worth watching and also just channel upon channel of crap.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got to thinking, how to do I get to find all the good tv, that I’m interested in watching nowadays. Largely I’m just flicking thru channels and find something, there are also some decent tv listings sites. But I wondered if there’s not a better way. Really I want to be able to find tv shows based on a load of symantec data. I want to be able to say I’m interested in these topics, now plot me a days tv watching based on my interests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other thing that occurs to me is what will the future of tv broadcasting and scheduling look like. It’s already less linear than it was with things like iplayer and itv on demand etc.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So when there’s a cloud of recorded shows floating around in the ether what’s going to be the method for scheduling shows then, will it be entirely pulled by the user or will broadcasters broadcast a set schedule even though you can realistically watch the show whenever?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wonder what the industry has in mind? I also wonder what users want? The schedule provides a pattern to life and familiarity where as everything on demand means that discussing tv is no longer as useful a social currency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eBooks – Publishers Don’t Screw The Pooch on This One Please</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/ebooks-publishers-dont-screw-the-pooch-on-this-one-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 11:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/ebooks-publishers-dont-screw-the-pooch-on-this-one-please/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webheat.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/ipad_hero.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-57&#34; title=&#34;ipad_hero&#34; src=&#34;http://www.webheat.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/ipad_hero-220x300.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;220&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’d &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; to buy an eBook Reader, I pretty much have the one I want picked out too, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mybebook.com/6-inch-ereaders/c14/p5/bebook-one-ereader/product_info.html&#34;&gt;BeBook One&lt;/a&gt; however I’m being a bit cautious here.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Since Apple have launched their iPad I’m really hoping that Publishers don’t cock this up. I don’t have anything against the iPad, it’s just not an eBook Reader, it doesn’t have ePaper and so the reading experience is going to hard on the eyes for a full book.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But where I worry publishers might really screw the pooch with the iPad is by losing the point of what a book is. A  book is a collection of information, whether that’s a story or a text book. If you watch &lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/5485150/penguins-incredible-vision-of-books-on-the-ipad-doesnt-look-anything-like-books&#34;&gt;Penguin Books’ iPad presentation here&lt;/a&gt; you can see they want to make books a more interactive thing. Great, for kids books, and if done in the right way great for adult books. But these guys are publishers, not technologists and so unless they get the right people on board sooner rather than later books are going to get ugly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/kevinrose&#34;&gt;Kevin Rose&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://digg.com&#34;&gt;Digg.com&lt;/a&gt; spoke about some of the possibilities for ebooks on the iPad with some interesting ideas. I like the idea of linking the book with your social networks. So as you’re reading you can see who else you know is reading this book, chapter, even page. I like the idea for encyclopaedias of making them media rich, and  hyperlinking. So you’re reading something about Winston Churchill and you can play a video or audio clip of one of his speeches. Then it says about Sir Anthony Eden, the Prime Minister who followed after Churchill with a link to the entry. Penguin, comparatively, look like they might be going over the top.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My other fear is that publishers will panda to the iPad and make these bright colourful media rich eBooks that will be no use on eBook readers. From what I understand about &lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/5478842/giz-explains-how-youre-gonna-get-screwed-by-ebook-formats&#34;&gt;eBook formats&lt;/a&gt; the iPad eBooks that Penguin are looking to publish are in ePub format. Which is a format readable by eBook readers, but how will it look? Are they testing their books on these readers too.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If I buy my BeBook One now will it be obsolete by the end of the year?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My last concern, I’d like to be able to replace all my current books with eBooks so I keep my existing library and can add to it in the future. However not every book coming out is available as an eBook. Publishers really need to pull their finger out on this. Embrace that this change is here and work out their position on it. I hope that publishers have a road map here and that they are talking to the hardware providers too.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smarter Washing Machines to Tell You When You’ve Left Stuff In Your Pockets</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/smarter-washing-machines-to-tell-you-when-youve-left-stuff-in-your-pockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 14:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/smarter-washing-machines-to-tell-you-when-youve-left-stuff-in-your-pockets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a half formed thought so far but I’m banging it up here anyway. Can we make washing machines that detect if there’s something in your pockets?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;All clothes come down to a few basic materials, so if you could eliminate those materials anything else left must be a foreign body that perhaps shouldn’t be in the washing machine and the user alerted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth Hearing Aid</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/bluetooth-hearing-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/bluetooth-hearing-aid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A colleague of mine, Dan Shane, suggested to me today a good topic to post on my site would be bluetooth hearing aids.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A quick Google around shows that someone beat him too the idea first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oticon.com/com/OurProducts/ConsumerProducts/Dual/Colours/show.html&#34;&gt;for example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There’s also a walk through of how to make your own: &lt;a title=&#34;make your own bluetooth hearing aid walk through&#34; href=&#34;http://gfern.com/btha/btha.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gfern.com/btha/btha.html&#34;&gt;http://gfern.com/btha/btha.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s certainly a great idea. If/when I lose my hearing and have to have a hearing aid then why not make it a bluetooth one that I can connect to my iphone, ipod, tv and any other audio devices that I have in the house so that I can just have the sound straight into my ear rather than making them loud enough for the hearing aid to pick up and amplify.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Foot Print Earphone Plugs</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/zero-foot-print-earphone-plugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 11:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/zero-foot-print-earphone-plugs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this crazy world where you can buy a 64GB usb drive that is little bigger than the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markstechnologynews.com/2008/11/buffalo-japan-launches-tiny-microsd.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;USB plug&lt;/a&gt; itself how comes ear phones still have a zonking great big plug on them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What we need for our iPod/iPhone and other PMPs is a zero (or near enough) foot print earphone plug.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If the cable was strengthened near the socket than that could be used to pull the plug out, eliminating the bulky plug entirely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Compact Living</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/compact-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2010 09:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/compact-living/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After moving flat time and time again one thing is true of all rented accommodation it seems. There is very little storage. I appreciate space is at a premium these days but some places I’ve lived have been pretty ridiculous.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;One thing that you’ll need in most flat is a mop and bucket, and one thing that’s not so compact is a bucket. Usually unsightly enough that you want to squirrel them away when the Jones’s come round but if you don’t have the storage space what do you do.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;One solution is this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; title=&#34;Fold Up Bucket&#34; src=&#34;http://www.frost.co.uk/images/product_images/large/9107.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fold Up Bucket&#34; width=&#34;114&#34; height=&#34;128&#34; /&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;which is definitely a space saver for the car washing amongst you, however I’d like something with some structural integrity so that I could wring out a mop on the top of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’d been mulling this over on and off for a while and I was always trying to work out a way for joints and hinges that enabled the folding up of such a invention to be water/air tight. It struck me today that I’d been thinking of the problem from the wrong angle and I didn’t need water/air tight hinges I just needed a plastic bladder inside the bucket that was flexible so the hard structure could create the rigidity and the fold down method and the bladder could create the water seal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another application for this idea is collapsible lunch boxes.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;When I was working up town I used to take a packed lunch with me most days and it was pretty much the only thing I was taking with me, and it was somewhat bulky. But carrying the empty lunch box home with me meant that I was carrying bulky nothingness with me. If I could collapse my lunch box I’d reclaim all that space again.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MikeD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone Frequently Used Apps</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/iphone-frequently-used-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2010 15:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/iphone-frequently-used-apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The iPhone, and the iPod touch’s navigation is fine…. whilst you only have a couple of pages of apps installed. But once you get five pages of apps installed it starts to get a little impractical.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seeing as last time I suggested to a friend that it would be good to be able to arrange the icons on your computer, thru iTunes or such, it was announced at the very next apple conference and released in that version of iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So my suggestion to get in before the next Apple conference on the 27th, is not a major overhaul of the UI, but simply to give a page or two to the fix icons down the bottom of the iPhone/iPod Touch UI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webheat.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/iphone.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-18&#34; title=&#34;iphone&#34; src=&#34;http://www.webheat.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/iphone-264x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iPhone UI&#34; width=&#34;264&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Here you can see the iPhone UI with the default icons in the fixed ‘dock’ at the bottom. I’m simply suggesting allowing that to be 2 pages that you can swipe between to allow 8 icons that are fixed, independently of the other pages of icons above it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You’d only have to swipe one way or another to get to the call functions etc but could access a further 4 apps easily and quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MikeD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OLED Wallpaper and all that comes with it</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/oled-wallpaper-and-all-that-comes-with-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 14:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/oled-wallpaper-and-all-that-comes-with-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not long after OLED first came to light I began, as I’m sure many futurists did, thinking about the ramifications of it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I considered the many applications that would be useful initially as things like the roll out screens that were already being discussed at this point. However what I went on to was marvelling at the possible future of OLED wallpaper where by a whole wall or your whole room/house is wallpapered with OLED paper.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The use of this becomes nearly as limiteless as you can imagine. You can pick and choose your wallpaper on a daily basis with next to no effort, you could have it randomly changing like your desktop wallpaper. You could wake to an epic sunrise and fall asleep to a beautiful sunset, you could gaze at the stars or watch the Aurora Borealis, all from the comfort of your own home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then consider that OLED tv will soon be with us and you can imagine the next convergence technology that’s hot will be TVs sold and OLED wallpaper. Imagine being able to sit in your front room and decide you want a 52″ tv on your wall right in front of your line of vision, with a few gestures recognized by the system controlling your OLED wallpaper image their you have it. You want to do some work on your computer whilst watching tv, you gesture into existence a 15″ monitor on the wall next to the tv and using a remote device or maybe more high definition gesture recognition where you type in on a projected keyboard on your lap, you tap away on a few emails.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few friend drop round and you want to watch a film together so you gesture the screen larger on your wall to fill the whole wall and enjoy a film together.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next day you’re off to a meeting at a clients office in a part of town you don’t know, you bring up Google maps and your email on your wall, you copy and paste the address into Google maps and find it, you hit street view to help you get your bearing ahead of time and your are immersed in a full wall street view that you can drag around to see where the office is, where’s the nearest place to get coffee and lunch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next step from this is of course full wall video conferencing, your room can easily become an immersive  multi-environment. For example, you could chat with friends from around the world and all feel like you’re sitting in the same room, you could virtually be in the office at your desk, seeing other’s sitting at their desks, all on your walls. You could play a game panning round your whole room, checking behind you before looking round the corner and rushing the guard.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is all surely just the tip of the ice berg for OLED wallpaper with the innovative minds of  the world coming up with creative ways of rendering content from all forms of media and sources on your wall in beautiful ways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MikeD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing my thoughts before the mecons get them!</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/publishing-my-thoughts-before-the-mecons-get-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/publishing-my-thoughts-before-the-mecons-get-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As someone who is naturally very creative and also naturally very lazy I’ve always been one to have bright ideas but not to put them into action.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s come to my attention lately that my ideas are becoming predictions and several of my ideas have crept into the real world without my participation. Now I’m by no means saying that pixies are coming and stealing my thoughts in the night but I wanted to make my ideas sort of open source. An open source idea would be one that anyone could act on but that I would be credited for coming up with the initial idea, no financial motives here, just pure ego.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following posts will detail an idea of mine as thoroughly as I can.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MikeD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>