<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scheduling on MikeDixson.com</title>
    <link>https://mikedixson.com/tags/scheduling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scheduling on MikeDixson.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:18:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mikedixson.com/tags/scheduling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Semantic TV guides, the future of tv</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/semantic-tv-guides-the-future-of-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/semantic-tv-guides-the-future-of-tv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been laid up lately with a broken leg and consequentially I’ve been watching a lot of tv. I’ve been surprised that there’s actually &lt;strong&gt;some&lt;/strong&gt; good shows out there worth watching and also just channel upon channel of crap.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got to thinking, how to do I get to find all the good tv, that I’m interested in watching nowadays. Largely I’m just flicking thru channels and find something, there are also some decent tv listings sites. But I wondered if there’s not a better way. Really I want to be able to find tv shows based on a load of symantec data. I want to be able to say I’m interested in these topics, now plot me a days tv watching based on my interests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other thing that occurs to me is what will the future of tv broadcasting and scheduling look like. It’s already less linear than it was with things like iplayer and itv on demand etc.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So when there’s a cloud of recorded shows floating around in the ether what’s going to be the method for scheduling shows then, will it be entirely pulled by the user or will broadcasters broadcast a set schedule even though you can realistically watch the show whenever?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wonder what the industry has in mind? I also wonder what users want? The schedule provides a pattern to life and familiarity where as everything on demand means that discussing tv is no longer as useful a social currency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>