<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exercise on MikeDixson.com</title>
    <link>https://mikedixson.com/tags/exercise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exercise on MikeDixson.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 13:59:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mikedixson.com/tags/exercise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>14 Stone Wobble</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/14-stone-wobble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 13:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/14-stone-wobble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well I knew I’d put on some weight, but was shocked to see the scale telling me I was 14 Stone this morning.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So now it’s time to sort this out, and in a stable and maintainable way too. So firstly I’ll start with the easy kills. I drink a lot of cola, so I’m going to kill that completely. That’s one of the easiest ways for me to lose weight and fat so it’s a no brainer. I think the next thing to do is start food shopping better. It’s too easy to pick up things in the shop that you can just slam in the oven or microwave and then eat, but invariably they are not the healthy choices.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So I’m going to put a bit more mindfulness into my shopping. Stir fry isn’t a bad option, especially with the veg to meat ratio I cook it with, so I’ll buy plenty of ingredients for that. I’ll also look on &lt;a title=&#34;BBC Good Food Guide&#34; href=&#34;http://www.bbcgoodfood.com/content/healthy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbcgoodfood.com/content/healthy/&#34;&gt;http://www.bbcgoodfood.com/content/healthy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for some recipes. As far as I know it can even make you your shopping list. So it should be another relatively easy to make healthy choice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Next comes increasing my exercise. About a year ago I was hitting the gym around 6 times a week and loving it. I had a nice little set up where I could easily go to two different branches of a gym, one I preferred for the weights set up, but was farther away and so I’d cycle there for my warm up, and another that was close enough that I could go before work without being late.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I’ve changed flats and gyms since and I’ve not managed to fit the gym in so neatly and so it’s rather fallen by the wayside. So I need to think up the best way for me to start slipping in exercise into my daily routine easily first. Once I get back into my passion for it will take over and I’ll be exercising more easily.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This one is going to require some thought, but there are a few options. I still have my gym membership, and so just need to work out what evenings I head to the gym instead of home or elsewhere. I also can ride to work. I’ve not tried it from this current flat, so I will give that a go next week and see how that goes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My will to cycle into work will be heavily affected by the weather, and so I can’t count on it as a form of regular exercise, just as a supplemental.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s see how I get on. &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; class=&#34;alignleft&#34; title=&#34;Man Boobs&#34; src=&#34;http://www.topnews.in/health/files/fat-heart.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;307&#34; height=&#34;203&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>