<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>US on MikeDixson.com</title>
    <link>https://mikedixson.com/tags/us/</link>
    <description>Recent content in US on MikeDixson.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:39:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mikedixson.com/tags/us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SOPA and PIPA Alternatives</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/sopa-and-pipa-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/sopa-and-pipa-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOPA and PIPA seek to prevent and punish piracy thru&lt;/strong&gt; law and technical obstruction. Piracy, is wrong, most of us have pirated something in our time, even if it was copying a friends cassette or cd so you could have a copy of an album your mate owns, in our hearts we all know we’re being a little bit naughty when we do it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing, the &lt;strong&gt;music and film industry don’t care too much if you are recording a film off TV&lt;/strong&gt; at home that they own the rights too, or record a copy of a song off the radio. It’s small scale, it’s not really affecting their bottom line.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;They care when it starts to make their fat wallets thinner and makes them look inaffective at protecting their intellectual properly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However the gist of it is that as long as the amount of &lt;strong&gt;legal plays/buys of a song/movie Vs the amount of pirated copies of a song or movie&lt;/strong&gt; is in their favour and keeps their wallets fat they won’t really give a rats arse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;why not embrace the new digital landscape&lt;/strong&gt;, why not make music and movies so easy to get and reasonably priced that piracy seems like idiocy?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Since buying a Spotify premium account subscription I’ve been lovingly listening to more new albums than I ever did before. I’ve been able to share these tracks via Spotify to friends and colleagues, and instead of a radio playing in the office now we have Spotify playing with a collaborative playlist that we all add tracks to. &lt;strong&gt;We have our own, very eclectic, radio station thru Spotify&lt;/strong&gt; and it’s exposing colleagues to new tracks continually.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the recent launch of Netflix in the UK, I’ve watched films and tv series, old and new, much of which is shared on my Facebook timeline and I’ve recommended films, and Netflix to friends.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So why is the film and music industry trying to make it so hard for me to get a hold of the product that they want me to have. &lt;strong&gt;Just make it easy and cheap enough and we’ll take the deal&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The downside to this streaming, legitimate consumption of movies and music is that some labels and/or artists choose not to release their product this way, and some major labels release their latest products.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I look forward to watching Netflix deal grow in the UK so their provision grows, and I look forward to being able to get hold of the latest albums immediately on Spotify.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Why record, movie companies and artists feel the need to be so prohibitive and restrictive in this I don’t know. They seem to be scared of technology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The message is simple, &lt;strong&gt;make the gatorade taste nice and we’ll gladly gulp it down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>