<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on MikeDixson.com</title>
    <link>https://mikedixson.com/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on MikeDixson.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 15:31:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mikedixson.com/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fixed: Obelisk not working in Ableton Live</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/fixed-obelisk-not-working-in-ableton-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 15:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/fixed-obelisk-not-working-in-ableton-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So when using the Frozen Plains Obelisk plugin in Ableton live 10 (I’m running10.1.15) following Frozen Plains instructions doesn’t work.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If you change the 2nd drop down on the synth/instrument track to Obelisk64 instead of Pre FX then it will work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, if you don’t want record a whole extra midi track for the Obelisk track then instead of arming both track, just set to Obelisk track to In on the monitoring and then arm the instrument you want to record. This has the added benefit of being able to easily have multiple instruments using Obelisk and switch to record on whichever one you want to play&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; width=&#34;285&#34; height=&#34;568&#34; src=&#34;https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/image.png&#34; alt=&#34;Ideal Obelisk and instrument settings.&#xA;Obelisk midi track set to monitor In.&#xA;Two different mini instrument tracks set to Obelisk64 instrument In and Obelisk64 instead of Pre FX or Post FX. One instrument track armed.&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-835&#34; srcset=&#34;https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/image.png 285w, https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/image-151x300.png 151w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 285px) 100vw, 285px&#34; /&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Musical Instrument Frequency Range Chart</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/musical-instrument-frequency-range-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 16:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/musical-instrument-frequency-range-chart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; width=&#34;1008&#34; height=&#34;1584&#34; src=&#34;https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/music_instruments_frequencies.gif?fit=604%2C949&amp;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-832&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;It looks like the original website is now unavailable and so I’m posting this here to share as the only other place it’s online it bloody Pinterest&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bordering On Obsession Released!</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/bordering-on-obsession-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 16:01:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/bordering-on-obsession-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;has-background has-light-green-cyan-background-color&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Over the summer I took part in a song writing game/mission with other songwriters on the web and one of the resultant songs that came out of the exercise was Bordering on Obsession, a song about lost loves, aspirations and self examination.&lt;br /&gt;In the wasteland that is the gameified app dating scene obsessing over looks, both your own and other peoples, and casually swiping your way thru an endless sea of fish you&amp;#8217;ll never catch is all the more a horrid obsession fueling activity.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&#34;has-background has-pale-pink-background-color&#34;&gt;&#xA;  You can stream or buy/download Bordering On Obsession now:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://distrokid.com/hyperfollow/mikedixson/ffym&#34;&gt;https://distrokid.com/hyperfollow/mikedixson/ffym&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; width=&#34;1500&#34; height=&#34;1500&#34; src=&#34;https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Bordering-On-Obsession-Cover-Art.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-773&#34; srcset=&#34;https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Bordering-On-Obsession-Cover-Art.jpg 1500w, https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Bordering-On-Obsession-Cover-Art-300x300.jpg 300w, https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Bordering-On-Obsession-Cover-Art-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Bordering-On-Obsession-Cover-Art-150x150.jpg 150w, https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Bordering-On-Obsession-Cover-Art-768x768.jpg 768w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 1500px) 100vw, 1500px&#34; /&gt; &lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom Fit Keyboard Dust Covers UK</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/custom-fit-keyboard-dust-covers-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 09:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/custom-fit-keyboard-dust-covers-uk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had such a hard time finding a dust cover to cover my Akai MPK249&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve just placed an order with this company&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pianocoversonline.co.uk/universal-keyboard-dust-covers-p-13026.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pianocoversonline.co.uk/universal-keyboard-dust-covers-p-13026.html&#34;&gt;http://www.pianocoversonline.co.uk/universal-keyboard-dust-covers-p-13026.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst it took a whilst to be delivered, which is fair enough, they were hand making it to order, I’m very happy with my keyboard cover.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll definitely use this company again for when I inevitably buy a full size keyboard 🙂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Project: Battery Powered Sonos Play:1</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/weekend-project-battery-powered-sonos-play1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 11:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/weekend-project-battery-powered-sonos-play1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following this video guide and the step up booster converter from ebay below I’m going to make a Sonos Play:1 battery powered so I can enjoy some lovely music on the balcony over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/XL6009-DC-DC-Voltage-Step-Up-Boost-Converter-replace-LM2577-3-32v-input-UK-Fast-/400858208676&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/XL6009-DC-DC-Voltage-Step-Up-Boost-Converter-replace-LM2577-3-32v-input-UK-Fast-/400858208676&#34;&gt;http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/XL6009-DC-DC-Voltage-Step-Up-Boost-Converter-replace-LM2577-3-32v-input-UK-Fast-/400858208676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOLVED: Spotify desktop client communication failed</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/solved-spotify-desktop-client-communication-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 12:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/solved-spotify-desktop-client-communication-failed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you receive the message &lt;strong&gt;Spotify desktop client communicat&lt;wbr /&gt;ion failed&lt;/strong&gt; when trying to &lt;strong&gt;Login with Facebook&lt;/strong&gt; to the Spotify app here’s why and how to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;reason&#34;&gt;Reason&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was because I have 2 factor security turned on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resolution&#34;&gt;Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;Go to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=security&amp;#038;view&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=security&amp;amp;view&#34;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=security&amp;amp;view&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;On the line App Passwords click &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;Generate App Passwords&lt;/strong&gt; link&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;Generate App Passwords&lt;/strong&gt; button&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;Enter a friendly name for what this is for i.e. Spotify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Generate Password&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;Copy the password in the &lt;strong&gt;normal&lt;/strong&gt; spotify logon password box.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;enter your FB email address as the username.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;HEY PRESTO!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Stop iTunes from Opening Automatically When You Press the Play/Pause Key on your Mac</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/how-to-stop-itunes-from-opening-automatically-when-you-press-the-playpause-key-on-your-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 12:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/how-to-stop-itunes-from-opening-automatically-when-you-press-the-playpause-key-on-your-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 class=&#34;entry-title&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: normal; color: #444444;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  How to Stop iTunes from Opening Automatically When You Press the Play/Pause Key on your Mac&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;How to Stop iTunes from Opening Automatically When You Press the Play/Pause Key on your Mac&#34; href=&#34;http://www.freakified.net/tutorials/how-to-stop-itunes-from-opening-automatically-when-you-press-the-playpause-key-on-your-mac/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freakified.net/tutorials/how-to-stop-itunes-from-opening-automatically-when-you-press-the-playpause-key-on-your-mac/&#34;&gt;http://www.freakified.net/tutorials/how-to-stop-itunes-from-opening-automatically-when-you-press-the-playpause-key-on-your-mac/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lyrical Challenges – Tips To Write Song Lyrics</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/lyrical-challenges-tips-to-write-song-lyrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 14:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/lyrical-challenges-tips-to-write-song-lyrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.snell-pym.org.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;friend&lt;/a&gt; asked me to write a piece on setting lyrical challenges for myself so I thought I’d post it here as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-goal-is-to-have-a-goal&#34;&gt;The Goal is to Have a Goal&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First things first. When setting a lyric challenge having a goal is the key. If you’ve got no reason to write a song you won’t get a word written down.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Often the reason is heartbreak or sitting there bored with your guitar in hand and happening upon something to explore. Setting a goal with a song challenge is a more proactive way of writing songs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once you have a goal you have something to work towards, whether it’s write one song by the end of the day, or write a song a day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-creative-goal&#34;&gt;A Creative Goal&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next thing is to have a goal that inspires some interesting creative angles. It’s very easy to become stale in musical style and lyrical theme, something to put your outside your comfort zone, but also something to make you take different approaches to those you’d would normally take.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instance, a title for a song normally doesn’t come to mind till you’ve written a song. Start with a handful of titles, pick one and and explore what it could mean.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;“See you on the other side of goodbye” –&lt;/em&gt; Could be about the end of a relationship, or it could be about what happens after a relationship has ended and lovers want to remain friends. Or it could be about someone dying and the morning process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;your-starter-for-10&#34;&gt;Your Starter For 10&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ok so there’s a few suggestions for lyrical challenges to get your started&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Title Ideas &lt;a title=&#34;Daily Title Ideas &#34; href=&#34;http://www.lyricideas.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lyricideas.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.lyricideas.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; – Lists 10 potential song titles (and lyrics) per day&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write a Reply – Find a favourite song and write a reply song&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A novel idea – Try and capture the main theme of a favourite character in a novel in a song&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;5 Minute Rush – A great way to quiet your inner critic set a timer and write as much of a song as you can in 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change Position – If you’re songs are normally written in the first person, or normally from a narrator’s point of view then switch it up. Force yourself to use another perspective.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One a Day – Similar to some bloggers, taking a 30 day challenge of a song. Write one song a day for 30 days. It doesn’t have to be a good song. But the act of writing every day will encourage your brain to generate more lyrics all the time and doing anything for 30 days in a row is a great way of starting to form a habit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;take-advantage-of-your-little-thoughts&#34;&gt;Take Advantage Of Your Little Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whilst this doesn’t quite fit in as a challenge, I implore every lyricist to buy some of these &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Cahier-Plain-Pocket-Journal-Brown/dp/8883704940&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;soft pocket notebooks&lt;/a&gt; and carrying one of these &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Fisher-Bullet-Space-Pen-Chrome/dp/B000095K9D/ref=tag_stp_s2_edpp_url&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;very pocketable pens&lt;/a&gt; and take them absolutely everywhere with you! The times when I’ve written the most lyrics are the times when I’m most idea and my brain has time to wander.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I might have a few minutes on a bus or a tube and my mind idly wanders through one thought or another, maybe driven by what I see in front of me, or maybe I’m lost in my own mind. But then BAM! I’m hit but a beautiful turn of phrase or way of perceiving something that I’d not thought of before.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If I can capture that right there and then I have a chance of working it into a song.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Otherwise it’s gone forever!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to mimic this spontaneous note taking using my ever-present smart phone instead. However there’s something so unforgiving about typing text into a phone that means I lose the meaning almost as much as if I’d never written it down at all.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good luck with your lyric writing!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SOPA and PIPA Alternatives</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/sopa-and-pipa-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/sopa-and-pipa-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOPA and PIPA seek to prevent and punish piracy thru&lt;/strong&gt; law and technical obstruction. Piracy, is wrong, most of us have pirated something in our time, even if it was copying a friends cassette or cd so you could have a copy of an album your mate owns, in our hearts we all know we’re being a little bit naughty when we do it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing, the &lt;strong&gt;music and film industry don’t care too much if you are recording a film off TV&lt;/strong&gt; at home that they own the rights too, or record a copy of a song off the radio. It’s small scale, it’s not really affecting their bottom line.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;They care when it starts to make their fat wallets thinner and makes them look inaffective at protecting their intellectual properly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However the gist of it is that as long as the amount of &lt;strong&gt;legal plays/buys of a song/movie Vs the amount of pirated copies of a song or movie&lt;/strong&gt; is in their favour and keeps their wallets fat they won’t really give a rats arse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;why not embrace the new digital landscape&lt;/strong&gt;, why not make music and movies so easy to get and reasonably priced that piracy seems like idiocy?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Since buying a Spotify premium account subscription I’ve been lovingly listening to more new albums than I ever did before. I’ve been able to share these tracks via Spotify to friends and colleagues, and instead of a radio playing in the office now we have Spotify playing with a collaborative playlist that we all add tracks to. &lt;strong&gt;We have our own, very eclectic, radio station thru Spotify&lt;/strong&gt; and it’s exposing colleagues to new tracks continually.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the recent launch of Netflix in the UK, I’ve watched films and tv series, old and new, much of which is shared on my Facebook timeline and I’ve recommended films, and Netflix to friends.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So why is the film and music industry trying to make it so hard for me to get a hold of the product that they want me to have. &lt;strong&gt;Just make it easy and cheap enough and we’ll take the deal&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The downside to this streaming, legitimate consumption of movies and music is that some labels and/or artists choose not to release their product this way, and some major labels release their latest products.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I look forward to watching Netflix deal grow in the UK so their provision grows, and I look forward to being able to get hold of the latest albums immediately on Spotify.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Why record, movie companies and artists feel the need to be so prohibitive and restrictive in this I don’t know. They seem to be scared of technology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The message is simple, &lt;strong&gt;make the gatorade taste nice and we’ll gladly gulp it down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>