<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wallpaper on MikeDixson.com</title>
    <link>https://mikedixson.com/tags/wallpaper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wallpaper on MikeDixson.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 12:44:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mikedixson.com/tags/wallpaper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Landscapify – Adjusting Portrait Photos for Landscape Frames</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/landscapify-adjusting-portrait-photos-for-landscape-frames/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 12:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/landscapify-adjusting-portrait-photos-for-landscape-frames/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been making a lot more use of my digital photo frame since I moved into my flat but a fair few of the photos I want to make use of are portrait orientation whilst the majority are landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a load of photos I’ve gone thru them and manually made them landscape by using a method I noticed that You’ve Been Framed use when viewers send in mobile footage shot in the wrong orientation for tv. The technique is to enlarge a second copy of the image/video as a background layer to fit the width of the landscape orientation and blur the background.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I figured as I’d want to do this to a lot of images over time I’d make a script to do so. So using Photoshop’s Actions I’ve done so and thought I’d share it: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Landscapify-Mike-Dixson.atn_.zip&#34;&gt;Landscapify – Mike Dixson.atn&lt;/a&gt; Here’s how to load the actions into your Photoshop &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imphotography.com/downloads/installactions.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imphotography.com/downloads/installactions.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.imphotography.com/downloads/installactions.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Mikes-Photoshop-Actions.atn_.zip&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instructions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open Image&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the Actions Window click on Landscapify&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Click the Play Icon &amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When prompted for the new canvas size enter the current width as the height and the current height as the width&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Click Ok (if prompted that clipping will occur click Ok to that too&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You’re done 🙂&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;div id=&#39;gallery-3&#39; class=&#39;gallery galleryid-337 gallery-columns-2 gallery-size-thumbnail&#39;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figure class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;div class=&#39;gallery-icon portrait&#39;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#39;https://mikedixson.com/landscapify-adjusting-portrait-photos-for-landscape-frames/3d-summit-day-1-6386-pre-landscapified/&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/3D-Summit-Day-1-6386-pre-landscapified-150x150.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-340&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-340&#39;&gt; Portrait &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt; &#xA;  &lt;div class=&#39;gallery-icon landscape&#39;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#39;https://mikedixson.com/landscapify-adjusting-portrait-photos-for-landscape-frames/3d-summit-day-1-6386-landscapified/&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;https://mikedixson.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/3D-Summit-Day-1-6386-landscapified-150x150.jpg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; aria-describedby=&#34;gallery-3-341&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#39;wp-caption-text gallery-caption&#39; id=&#39;gallery-3-341&#39;&gt; Landscapified &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope it’s useful to you.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mike&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OLED Wallpaper and all that comes with it</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/oled-wallpaper-and-all-that-comes-with-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 14:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/oled-wallpaper-and-all-that-comes-with-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not long after OLED first came to light I began, as I’m sure many futurists did, thinking about the ramifications of it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I considered the many applications that would be useful initially as things like the roll out screens that were already being discussed at this point. However what I went on to was marvelling at the possible future of OLED wallpaper where by a whole wall or your whole room/house is wallpapered with OLED paper.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The use of this becomes nearly as limiteless as you can imagine. You can pick and choose your wallpaper on a daily basis with next to no effort, you could have it randomly changing like your desktop wallpaper. You could wake to an epic sunrise and fall asleep to a beautiful sunset, you could gaze at the stars or watch the Aurora Borealis, all from the comfort of your own home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then consider that OLED tv will soon be with us and you can imagine the next convergence technology that’s hot will be TVs sold and OLED wallpaper. Imagine being able to sit in your front room and decide you want a 52″ tv on your wall right in front of your line of vision, with a few gestures recognized by the system controlling your OLED wallpaper image their you have it. You want to do some work on your computer whilst watching tv, you gesture into existence a 15″ monitor on the wall next to the tv and using a remote device or maybe more high definition gesture recognition where you type in on a projected keyboard on your lap, you tap away on a few emails.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few friend drop round and you want to watch a film together so you gesture the screen larger on your wall to fill the whole wall and enjoy a film together.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next day you’re off to a meeting at a clients office in a part of town you don’t know, you bring up Google maps and your email on your wall, you copy and paste the address into Google maps and find it, you hit street view to help you get your bearing ahead of time and your are immersed in a full wall street view that you can drag around to see where the office is, where’s the nearest place to get coffee and lunch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next step from this is of course full wall video conferencing, your room can easily become an immersive  multi-environment. For example, you could chat with friends from around the world and all feel like you’re sitting in the same room, you could virtually be in the office at your desk, seeing other’s sitting at their desks, all on your walls. You could play a game panning round your whole room, checking behind you before looking round the corner and rushing the guard.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is all surely just the tip of the ice berg for OLED wallpaper with the innovative minds of  the world coming up with creative ways of rendering content from all forms of media and sources on your wall in beautiful ways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MikeD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>