<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on MikeDixson.com</title>
    <link>https://mikedixson.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on MikeDixson.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 23:36:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mikedixson.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What makes for a great blog post?</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/what-make-for-a-great-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 23:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/what-make-for-a-great-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been watching the stats lately on my blog. Always happy to see visitors, and hopeful that what I write is useful to people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got to thinking and a few google searches later leave me thinking that it’s nothing I didn’t know already.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-make-text-scannable&#34;&gt;1. Make text scannable&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not just to search engines, but most importantly the human eye. I always think newspapers are a great example of this. Headlines grab your attention and dangle their bait in front of you luring you into read the story.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using paragraphs and white space to break up the text well is another good tip, and another one well employed by newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-say-something-interesting&#34;&gt;2. Say something interesting&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is so obvious it’s obscene. If you’re not saying anything anyone wants to hear then why would anyone listen?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-speak-to-your-audience&#34;&gt;3. Speak to your audience&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This bit is maybe the hardest. Whilst I know who is most likely to read this at the moment, whilst it’s in it’s infancy, I hope to speak to a wider community.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I don’t really want to prescribe that but I guess I have to in a way so I’m speaking to you in the right way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-use-lists&#34;&gt;4. Use Lists&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who doesn’t love a list? High Fidelity’s Top 5 lists running throughout the film, the charts, your todo list. You might hate all the todos but having them in a list is your way to tame the those beasts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-use-pictures&#34;&gt;5. Use Pictures&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pictures scan well, grab attention quickly and add some eye candy that text just can’t cut. Often a photo can sum up a story quicker and give the reader more than you can say in a 1000 words.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-keep-it-short&#34;&gt;6. Keep it short&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Short and concise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>