<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Video on MikeDixson.com</title>
    <link>https://mikedixson.com/categories/video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video on MikeDixson.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 11:17:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mikedixson.com/categories/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Project: Battery Powered Sonos Play:1</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/weekend-project-battery-powered-sonos-play1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 11:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/weekend-project-battery-powered-sonos-play1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following this video guide and the step up booster converter from ebay below I’m going to make a Sonos Play:1 battery powered so I can enjoy some lovely music on the balcony over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/XL6009-DC-DC-Voltage-Step-Up-Boost-Converter-replace-LM2577-3-32v-input-UK-Fast-/400858208676&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/XL6009-DC-DC-Voltage-Step-Up-Boost-Converter-replace-LM2577-3-32v-input-UK-Fast-/400858208676&#34;&gt;http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/XL6009-DC-DC-Voltage-Step-Up-Boost-Converter-replace-LM2577-3-32v-input-UK-Fast-/400858208676&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semantic TV guides, the future of tv</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/semantic-tv-guides-the-future-of-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/semantic-tv-guides-the-future-of-tv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been laid up lately with a broken leg and consequentially I’ve been watching a lot of tv. I’ve been surprised that there’s actually &lt;strong&gt;some&lt;/strong&gt; good shows out there worth watching and also just channel upon channel of crap.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got to thinking, how to do I get to find all the good tv, that I’m interested in watching nowadays. Largely I’m just flicking thru channels and find something, there are also some decent tv listings sites. But I wondered if there’s not a better way. Really I want to be able to find tv shows based on a load of symantec data. I want to be able to say I’m interested in these topics, now plot me a days tv watching based on my interests.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other thing that occurs to me is what will the future of tv broadcasting and scheduling look like. It’s already less linear than it was with things like iplayer and itv on demand etc.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So when there’s a cloud of recorded shows floating around in the ether what’s going to be the method for scheduling shows then, will it be entirely pulled by the user or will broadcasters broadcast a set schedule even though you can realistically watch the show whenever?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wonder what the industry has in mind? I also wonder what users want? The schedule provides a pattern to life and familiarity where as everything on demand means that discussing tv is no longer as useful a social currency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OLED Wallpaper and all that comes with it</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/oled-wallpaper-and-all-that-comes-with-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 14:37:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/oled-wallpaper-and-all-that-comes-with-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not long after OLED first came to light I began, as I’m sure many futurists did, thinking about the ramifications of it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I considered the many applications that would be useful initially as things like the roll out screens that were already being discussed at this point. However what I went on to was marvelling at the possible future of OLED wallpaper where by a whole wall or your whole room/house is wallpapered with OLED paper.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The use of this becomes nearly as limiteless as you can imagine. You can pick and choose your wallpaper on a daily basis with next to no effort, you could have it randomly changing like your desktop wallpaper. You could wake to an epic sunrise and fall asleep to a beautiful sunset, you could gaze at the stars or watch the Aurora Borealis, all from the comfort of your own home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then consider that OLED tv will soon be with us and you can imagine the next convergence technology that’s hot will be TVs sold and OLED wallpaper. Imagine being able to sit in your front room and decide you want a 52″ tv on your wall right in front of your line of vision, with a few gestures recognized by the system controlling your OLED wallpaper image their you have it. You want to do some work on your computer whilst watching tv, you gesture into existence a 15″ monitor on the wall next to the tv and using a remote device or maybe more high definition gesture recognition where you type in on a projected keyboard on your lap, you tap away on a few emails.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few friend drop round and you want to watch a film together so you gesture the screen larger on your wall to fill the whole wall and enjoy a film together.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next day you’re off to a meeting at a clients office in a part of town you don’t know, you bring up Google maps and your email on your wall, you copy and paste the address into Google maps and find it, you hit street view to help you get your bearing ahead of time and your are immersed in a full wall street view that you can drag around to see where the office is, where’s the nearest place to get coffee and lunch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next step from this is of course full wall video conferencing, your room can easily become an immersive  multi-environment. For example, you could chat with friends from around the world and all feel like you’re sitting in the same room, you could virtually be in the office at your desk, seeing other’s sitting at their desks, all on your walls. You could play a game panning round your whole room, checking behind you before looking round the corner and rushing the guard.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is all surely just the tip of the ice berg for OLED wallpaper with the innovative minds of  the world coming up with creative ways of rendering content from all forms of media and sources on your wall in beautiful ways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MikeD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>