<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dieting on MikeDixson.com</title>
    <link>https://mikedixson.com/tags/dieting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dieting on MikeDixson.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 18:05:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mikedixson.com/tags/dieting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Fricking Love Coca Cola? Diet Update</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/i-fricking-love-coca-cola-diet-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 18:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/i-fricking-love-coca-cola-diet-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve managed to lose a bit of weight adjusting my diet as I &lt;a href=&#34;http://mikedixson.com/2012/04/first-wobbly-steps/&#34; title=&#34;First wobbly steps&#34;&gt;said I would&lt;/a&gt; but it’s not being as easy as I had first felt.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was ready to jump straight back into exercise, raring to go, but life doesn’t always work with your plans. A few unavoidable things have come up that have meant I’ve not always been able to cook for myself. However I have been making better choices largely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;frugle--not-fruity&#34;&gt;Frugle = Not Fruity&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One factor has made it hard to make as healthy choices as I’d like to though. Coca Cola’s evil work. I went to the cinema, as I don’t do it often so I decided a hot dog was an o.k. treat, not great, but o.k. as a treat. I just wanted a small drink of something healthy to wash it down with and drink thru the movie. However that was going to cost me a metric poop ton of money, but if I had a giant, and I mean as big as my head, cola, it would be cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &amp;#8220;WTF?&amp;#8221;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I bit the bullet and went for the cola, resolute to only drink what I needed from it, as little as possible. So aside from when I had a choking fit in the cinema and had to clear my throat I barely drunk any of this monster drink.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;fruit-juice-company8217s-need-to-be-slutty&#34;&gt;Fruit juice company’s need to be slutty&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If fruit juice companies start getting in bed with cinemas etc like Coke do then surely I could be drinking a lovely fruit juice or water or such, instead of this head sized carton of sugar?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;can-we-vote-with-our-feetmouths&#34;&gt;Can we vote with our feet/mouths?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When the choices are weighted as such can we be expected to vote with our feet/mouths as to what we’d rather have. If the prices were equal I probably would have had just a water that day as I’d already had a couple of fruit juices. But when the cinema tickets cost so much and the other food products cost are &lt;a title=&#34;Movie Theaters Make 85% Profit at Concession Stands  Read more: http://moneyland.time.com/2009/12/07/movie-theaters-make-85-profit-at-concession-stands/#ixzz1rqmHwC3W&#34; href=&#34;http://moneyland.time.com/2009/12/07/movie-theaters-make-85-profit-at-concession-stands/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;upto 85% profit&lt;/a&gt; then every penny starts to count.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I’m heading out to the cinema in the future I’ll be smuggling in a bottle of water. &lt;em&gt;I this what it’s come to?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First wobbly steps</title>
      <link>https://mikedixson.com/first-wobbly-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 23:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mikedixson.com/first-wobbly-steps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So since making my post &lt;a href=&#34;http://mikedixson.com/2012/03/14-stone-wobble/&#34;&gt;14 Stone Wobble&lt;/a&gt; I’ve been making the changes I said I would. So I have up’d my exercise amount, lowered the amount of food I’m eating, and I’m eating healthier foods.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It’s actually been pretty easy to make the changes. However what’s not been hard is being hungry all the time. The only time I’ve not been hungry is when I had a protein burst in the form of a turkey stir fry for dinner. Turkey being lower in fat than chicken. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully tomorrow will be easier as I cooked double the portions for dinner tonight and the other half is in the fridge for lunch tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I won’t blog continually about weight loss and such but these first few steps/changes are the important ones so I feel it’s best to put something down about them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>